

# AHMED ELSHABRAWY

Lecturer Assistant

# About Me

Motivated assistant lecturer in conservation with strong research potential and proven track record. Experienced in teaching practical courses for students. Adaptive, flexible, and proactive in new work environments.

- •
- 002 01064553131 002 - 01550409717
- A7med.shabrawy@Cu.edu.eg A7med.shabrawy@outlook.com
- 0

Conservation Dep., Faculty of Archaeology, Cairo University-Giza - Giza-Egypt.

# Language

- Arabic (Native)
- English (Fluent)
- French (Good)
- Spain (basic)

# Expertise

- Research Skills
- Teaching Skills
- Art Conservation Skills
- Documentation Skills
- Creativity
- Negotiation
- Critical Thinking
- Leadership

## Experience

#### **Lecturer Assistant**

Cairo University, Egypt: Jun. 2022 – present

Senior lecturer assistant in the Conservation of wall paintings. Teaching practical lectures and courses in Conservation to students in both the under and postgraduate stages.

#### **Demonstrator**

Cairo University, Egypt: Oct. 2016 - May 2022

Same duties as the lecturer assistant. Helping in preparing and teaching the practical courses with all materials of cultural heritage property.

#### Education

# Cairo University, Faculty of Archaeology Conservation Department

#### PhD Student, Nov. 2023 - present

Thesis Title- "Integrating AI-Driven Solutions for Condition Assessment, Automated Analysis, and Conservation of Wall Paintings: A Novel Multidisciplinary Approach for Cultural Heritage Protection".

#### Pre-PhD Course, Sep. 2022 - Jul. 2023

One academic year of studying some advanced courses in conservation science to pursue PhD studies.

#### MSc. In Conservation of wall paintings and reliefs, Mar. 2018 – May 2022

Thesis title "Study of Iron Compounds Effect on the Deterioration of Paint Layer in Wall Paintings and Reliefs, Treatment and Conservation Methods "Applied on a Selected Object."

Grade: Excellent: A 95% - Undersupervision of Prof.Dr.Mona Fouad Ali – 2022.

#### Pre-MSc. Course, Sep. 2016 - Jul. 2017

One academic year of studying some advanced courses in conservation science and conservation principles to pursue the master's studies. Excellent.

#### Bachelor of Science, Sep. 2011 - Jul. 2015

One academic year of studying some advanced courses in conservation science and conservation principles to pursue the master's studies. Excellent with Honors degree.

# Diploma, Technology University. Sep. 2011 – Jul. 2015

Graduated in the Department of Architectural Conservation, Technical Institute for Conservation. Excellent with honors degree.

#### Research Interests

- Conservation Sciences
- Artificial Intelligence
- Pigments and colorants
- Examination and Analysis
- Material science
- Nanomaterials
- Archaeometry
- Ethics and Protocols
- Microclimatic control
- Climate change

#### Skills

# <u>Te</u>chnical

- -Conservation of Art Works
- -2D and 3D documentation of monuments and historical buildings
- Programs: AutoCAD, 3DMax, 3Dzefyr, Photogrammetry Bundle, SketchUp, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Microsoft Office
- Scientific software: Match!, XRD,

QXRD, Profex, Origin, Spectragryph,

FTIR Essential, Mountain, SPSS.

Programming: Python, SQL, LLM , and

Data Science (Self-Learning Beginner)

### Personal

Photography, painting, traveling, volleyball, Designs, programming, and Self Learning

#### Soft skills

Effective Communication, Critical Thinking, Leadership, Interpersonal, Problem-Solving, Adaptability, Time Management, Attention to Detail, Project Management, and Cultural Sensitivity.

All references are available upon on request

# publications and Presentations

- Elshabrawy, A. (2023). Assessment of the use of innovative methods and digital restoration in the development of archaeological heritage sites. In Athar, Research on Heritage Impact Assessment: ALULA international conference on Heritage Impact Assessment (ISBN: 978-9953-591-75-9).pp 571-585
- Elshabrawy, A. (2022) Rock Varnish Crusts in Archaeological Sites Between Deterioration and Sustainable Conservation In light of Climate Change - The current situation and the future of Egyptian antiquities in light of climate change conference - Scientific Research Academy- Egypt.
- Elshabrawy, A., Ali, M. (2021). 'Characterization of Rock Varnish Ferromanganese Crusts on Ancient Egyptian Wall Paintings from Bahariya Oasis, Egypt,' Shedet, 8(8), pp. 168-185. doi: 10.21608/shedet.2021.207866
- Elshabrawy, A., Algohary, M.(2021). Artificial intelligence applications in the imaginary conservation of historic collections and buildings protect their authenticity against theft and forgery- Applications of artificial intelligence in the social sciences and humanities, Characteristics - Software - Implementation Mechanisms conference - Faculty of Arts, Cairo University-Egypt.
- Elshabrawy, A., Algohary, M.(2021). Documentation of Museum collection with Photogrammetry applications controlled with Al Applications of artificial intelligence in the social sciences and humanities, Characteristics Software Implementation Mechanisms conference Faculty of Arts, Cairo University-Egypt.

#### Activities

#### In my conservation work, I've:

- · Planned for the Mosque of Lady Houria in Beni Suef (2022).
- Conserved panel paintings at Deir Al-Malak church in Cairo (2020). Consulted on conservation plans for churches.
- · Preserved historical collections in Giza (2020).
- · Managed collections at La Charité de Saint Vincent in Cairo (2017).
- · Preserved churches in Cairo and Buhyira (2016).
- · Conserved Al-Azhar mosque in Cairo (2015).

#### **Current roles in University Community:**

- Director Board Member at the Center for Restoration, Cairo University (2022-present).
- •Member of Documentation Center of Cultural Heritage Civil Coordination (2021-present).
- Committee Member for Inventory of archaeological collections at Cairo University Civil Coordination (2022-present).
- •Council Member for Community Service and Environmental Development Affairs (2022-present).
- •Part of the Technical Office at the alliance of Greater Cairo universities (2024-present).
- •Member of Environmental and Community Awareness Committee (2023-present).

#### **Volunteering and Community Service**

- Participation in development convoys with Cairo University and Hayah Karima Foundation across various Egyptian regions (2020 - 2024)
- Workshops for children on handicrafts and social marketing, Cairo University initiatives (2022 2023).
- Workshops for Special Needs children on handicrafts and Art for self-expression and self-discovery (2024).
- -Participating in many external community activities to raise archaeological and environmental awareness for citizens and children (2018-2024).